Mr. Hanlin CAI

D.O.B. Nov. 01, 2002 | Tel: (+86) 15905925789 | hanlin.cai@ieee.org | https://caihanlin.com Building 7, Golden Garden, Quanzhou City, Fujian Province, China (362700)

OVERVIEW

As a highly motivated and collaborative student majoring in engineering, I have a strong interest in the industrial IoT system and cyber security. During undergraduate studies, I have gained valuable experience in sensor design, attack detection, and machine learning. This entails completing a six-month industrial internship, publishing three peer-reviewed papers, and securing five awards at the national level in competitions.

EDUCATION

Fuzhou University (FZU) (China-Ireland Cooperative Program)

Sep. 2020 - Jun. 2024

Bachelor of Engineering in Automation (Taught in English)

> Current GPA: 3.81/4.00 (Top 8%), Average Score: 88.38

National University of Ireland, Maynooth (MU)

Sep. 2020 - Jun. 2024

Bachelor of Science in Robotics and Intelligent Devices (Combined Degrees)

Expect to achieve First Class Honours (Third-year score: 88.7 | Ranking: 1/52)

Main Courses: Control System Design, Software Engineering, Operating System, Digital System, Real-time and Embedded System, Robotics and Automation, Algorithms and Data Structures, Machine Learning

- Course Projects: Industrial Internship Experience (97/100), Signals & Systems Integration Project (92/100)
- Scholarships: FEPG Scholarship (Highest Award at FZU, Top 0.5%), XiamenAir Scholarship (Top 1%), Best Academic Performance Award at MU (Top 2%), First Prize Scholarship at FZU (Top 2%, Three Times)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Embedded Development Intern, Huading Intelligent Manufacturing Technology Co. LTD., Fujian, China *Mentors: SN.ENGR Yuxiong Xia and Dr. Dan Chen*Outline:

Jan. 2023 – June 2023

- Successfully tackled the complexities of instrument inspection with intricate industrial environments by devising an intelligent inspection system leveraging IoT devices, quadruped robots and cloud computing.
 Key Responsibilities:
- Implemented real-time data collection of sensor modules using ESP32; Integrated machine control with visual algorithms to empower quadruped robots to extract and analyse images of industrial instruments.

 Achievement:
- Won the **Best Technology Award** in the 2023 China National Youth Science Innovation Project Competition.

Research Assistant, Laboratory of Industrial Automation Control Technology and Information Processing

Supervisors: Prof. Zhezhuang Xu and Dr. Yuan Meng

Oct. 2022 – Present

Outline:

- Addressed the security vulnerabilities and susceptibility to attacks in Bluetooth Low Energy Networks utilising a hybrid attack detection mechanism based on physical features and machine learning.
 Key Responsibilities:
- Established a BLE experimental platform, collected datasets using BLE Sniffer, nRF Connect and Wireshark.
- Developed an attack detection algorithm based on temporal convolutional network, text-CNN and SVM. **Achievement:**
- Secured a research grant over \$3000; Authored a research paper and submitted to **AAAI 2024** conference.

Visiting Student, Cambridge Centre for the Integration of Science, Technology and Culture (CCISTC)

Supervisor: Prof. Pietro Liò

June 2022 – Dec. 2022

Outline:

 Resolved the challenge of detecting multiple-mix-attacks within IoT networks by developing a detection framework that integrates reconstruction and classification learning approaches.

Key Responsibilities:

- Developed a multiple-mix-attacks detection algorithm based on LSTM model and random forest algorithm. **Achievement:**
- Research report achieved a ranking within top 5%; Won an outstanding oversea visiting scholarship (\$2400).

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] <u>Hanlin Cai</u>, Zheng Li, Jiaqi Hu, Wei Hong Lim, Sew Sun Tiang, Mastaneh Mokayef, Chin Hong Wong. "Optimising Traffic Sign Detection System Using Deep Residual Neural Networks Combined with Analytic Hierarchy Process Model". The 28th International Conference on Artificial Life and Robotics. Recommended for expanding publication in the Journal of Advances in Artificial Life Robotics, 2023.
- [2] <u>Hanlin Cai</u>, Jiaqi Hu, Zheng Li, Wei Hong Lim, Mastaneh Mokayef, Chin Hong Wong. "An IoT Garbage Monitoring System for Effective Garbage Management". The 4th International Conference on Computer Engineering, Network, and Intelligent Multimedia (IEEE CENIM), 2022.
- [3] <u>Hanlin Cai</u>, Yuchen Fang, Meng Yuan, Zhezhuang Xu. "BLEGuard: Hybrid Detection Mechanism for Spoofing Attacks in Bluetooth Low Energy Networks". The 38th AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (One of most important conferences for AI Research). Under review, 2024.
- [4] <u>Hanlin Cai</u>, Jiacheng Huang, Yuchen Fang, Shuying Liu, Wenzhuo Fan, Chen Dan, Zhezhuang Xu. "Detecting Multiple-mix-attack in IoT Networks through Reconstruction and Classification Machine Learning Techniques". Sensors Journal. Under review, 2024.

AWARDS & HONOURS

Finalist of China International Internet+ Innovation and Entrepreneurship Competition (Top 3%)	Oct. 2023
Best Technology Award in China National Youth Science Innovation Project Competition (Top 1%)	Aug. 2023
Second Prize in National Collegiate Internet of Things Technology and Application Competition	Aug. 2023
Finalist Award in International Mathematical Contest in Modeling (Top 1% of all 20508 paper)	May 2023
First Prize in China Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling (Top 5%)	Dec. 2022
Third Prize in Chinese National College Student Computer Design Competition	Aug. 2022
Outstanding volunteer in the 44th Session of the World Heritage Committee	July 2021

SKILLS & SPECIALTY

Language Skills: English (Fluent), Mandarin (Native), Hokkien (Native)

Programming: Python, MATLAB, Java, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bash, Markdown, LaTeX

Specialty: Swimming (Reached Chinese national second-level swimming athlete standard; **Championship** of 100-meter freestyle swimming competition of Fuzhou University in *June 2022*)

LEADERSHIP

Department of Volunteer Work, Youth League Committee of Fuzhou University

Deputy President (Mentor: Dr. Yixuan Hu)

Sep. 2021 - Sep. 2022

- Outline: Managed the planning, operation, and publicity of volunteer service work, and helped mentors to promote the improvement, digitisation and intelligence of volunteer service management.
- **Key Responsibilities:** Organised 39 activities (19 volunteer activities for epidemic prevention and control, 12 for community service, and 8 for environmental protection) with over 890 participants in related activities.
- **Achievement:** Responsible for the publicity work of 17 volunteer activities, with a total of more than 240,000 page views, covering more than 40,000 people. Personal volunteer service time exceeded 240 hours.